AASMA AAS MUHAMMAD

0092304-4099-635 • aasma.aas.muhammad@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/aasma-aas-muhammad-0a8726184/ • github.com/Aasma-Aas

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic Data Scientist with a solid foundation in front-end development having more than 2 years of experience, who wants to transition into the data science world. Experienced in various data science projects, including machine learning, deep learning, and web scraping. I am confident that my skills make me the best candidate for a data science role.

EXPERIENCE

Arhamsoft (Pvt) Ltd: FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

June 2021 - June 2023

- Developed fully responsive web designs primarily for blockchain projects (ReactJs, Vuejs), while also contributing to projects on WordPress, and Shopify platforms.
- Worked closely with designers to ensure the correct implementation of UI components, layouts and visuals.
- Designed an animated website using GSAP library in reactJs or simple javascript both.
- Developed a user-friendly interface for the blockchain project.
- Implemented various features and functionality using javascript, reactjs and jQuery.
- Tested the front-end side of the project and fix bugs if any.
- Collaborated with other developers to ensure the smooth functioning of the website.
- Ensured that all coding standards are followed while developing the website.

Information Technolgy development (ITD): FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Dec 2020 - May 2021

- Designed responsive websites using Html5, CSS3, Bootsrap5 and worked in wordpress projects.
- Responsible for designing HTML and testing which includes (browser tests) throughout the project from start to end.

AkzoNobel (PK): Intern

July 2017 – Aug 2017

- Closely work with the IT team to successfully implement the Cisco Telepresence project.
- Conducted in-depth exploration and analysis of the Cisco Telepresence technology to gain a comprehensive understanding of its functionalities and capabilities.
- Create detailed and informative manual documentation, ensuring clear guidelines for the setup, operation, and maintenance of the Cisco Telepresence system.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python| C# **Database:** SQL | Postgres

Web Technology: Javascript | Html | ReactJs | React Bootstrap | GSAP | Shopify Polaris | CSS | ¡Query | Tailwind

CSS

Libraries: Pandas | NumPy | Scikit-Learn | Matplotlib | Keras | Tensorflow

Data Science skills: Exploratory Data Analysis | Data Visualization | Feature Engineering | Machine Learning | Natural

Language Processing (NLP) | Computer Vision | Deep Learning | Web Scraping

Certifications:

- Machine Learning with Python IBM Skills Network
- · Building Deep Learning Models with TensorFlow Coursera
- Standford WIDS Datathon Workshop 2023 University of Management and Technology

EDUCATION

MS Computer Science

March 2022 - continue

3.48 GPA

University of Management and Technology, Pakistan

Relevant coursework: Advanced Algorithm Analysis, Computer vision, Natural Language Processing, Advanced Artificial intelligence

Master's Information and Communication Technology

Sep 2016 - Jan 2019

University of Management and Technology, Pakistan

Relevant coursework: Database, Object Oriented Programming, Advanced Computer Networks, Software Quality Assurance, Software Project Management

Bachelor Double Mathematics and Physics

March 2014 - Aug 2016

University of Punjab, Pakistan

Relevant coursework: Calculus with Analytic Geometry, Mathematical Methods, Calculus and Linear Algebra,

Physics(Mechanics + Waves and Oscillation + Thermodynamics + Electronics and Modern Physics)

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Thesis: Suspicious Activity Detection (UCF Crime images Dataset)

Spring 2023

Computer Vision: Image Recognition

Technology: CNN+LSTM, CNN+VGG16, Keras, transfer learning model (all type of DenseNet, Resnet and VGG16+19 NumPy, Python, Flask, OpenCV, Keres, TensorFlow

• A python-based application that can detect crime images (Robbery, Shoplifting, and Fighting) using deep learning models and along with that research paper is also written.

FYP: Journal Management System

Spring 2018

Web Development

Technology: Java, MySQL, JavaScript, Html, CSS, Bootstrap

The Journal Management System (JMS) is a web-based application developed using Java, designed to streamline
the process of article and research paper submission, review, and publication within the academic and research
community.

Alzheimer's Disease Prediction using Machine Learning With XAI

Fall 2022

Machine Learning: Classification

Technology: Python, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, matplotlib, SVM, AdaBoost, Logistic Regression, Random Forest, Explainable AI

 Classification of Alzheimer's disease where I have performed proper EDA in well manner apply ML algorithm to classify disease using trained dataset and I have also applied the Explainable AI technique Lime which highlights the most important features.

Chatbot using Dialogue Flow

Natural Language Processing

Technology: ReactJs, Python, Pandas, Dialogue Api

• Build the Chatbot using Dialogue Api and integrated into a user-friendly web page designed using ReactJs technology.

Web Scraping

Technology: Beautiful Soap, Python, Pandas,

Scaping of user views of thousands of products.

ACTIVITIES

VOLUNTEER of Local Government

2023 - present

Member of Management Committee